{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hugo Weaving","incorrectAnswers":["Tobey Maguire","Timothy Spall","Elijah Wood"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Matrix and Captain America: The First Avenger?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tequila","incorrectAnswers":["Guinness","Sang Som Rum","Sombai"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Mexico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dave Bautista","incorrectAnswers":["Jeremy Renner","Paul Rudd","Paul Bettany"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Drax the Destroyer in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"  A character in 'Moby Dick'","incorrectAnswers":[" The owner's dog","A comic book hero","The owner's childhood friend"],"question":"What was the Starbucks chain of coffee shops named after?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Red","Blue","Yellow"],"question":"What color is traditionally associated with Robin Hood's outfits on film and in illustrations?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"McDonald's","incorrectAnswers":["Burger King","KFC","Subway"],"question":"What fast food restaurant has Marilyn Monroe's star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame in front of it?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"USA","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Spain","The UK"],"question":"In which country would you find the Statue of Liberty?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'In Search of the Castaways'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Glen Campbell","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Dylan","Bruce Springsteen","Neil Young"],"question":"Which Singer Started As A Session Guitarist Working With The Likes Of Bobby Darin , Frank Sinatra, Dean Martin & The Beach Boys?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The World Trade Organization","incorrectAnswers":["The World Tourism Organization","The World Television Organization","The World Textile Organization"],"question":"What does the abbreviation 'WTO' stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"James Franco","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","Gary Oldman","Donald Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Spider-Man and Milk?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cairo","incorrectAnswers":["Muscat","Beirut","Haifa"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Egypt?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Immanuel Kant","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Spinoza","St. Augustine"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Morality is not the doctrine of how we may make ourselves happy, but of how we may make ourselves worthy of happiness'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Run a mile","incorrectAnswers":["Climb the Empire State building","Complete a 30,000 foot skydive","Swim the English channel"],"question":"In 1954, what did Roger Bannister become the first person to do in under four minutes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J.D Salinger","incorrectAnswers":["Henry Rollins","Chuck Palahnuik","Jack Kerouac"],"question":"Who Wrote The 1951 Novel The Catcher in the Rye?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kiwi","incorrectAnswers":["Emu","Penguin","Ostrich"],"question":"What is the name of the strictly protected bird, about the size of a chicken, that is native to New Zealand?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A brood","incorrectAnswers":["A stud","A paddling","A pack"],"question":"What is the word for a group of grouse?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Gustave Flaubert","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Twenty Years After'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Florida","incorrectAnswers":["Kansas","Texas","California"],"question":"Which American state's name is Spanish for \"flowered\" or \"flowery land\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Barry Sonnenfeld","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Men in Black?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodwind","incorrectAnswers":["Stringed","Percussion","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument is a saxophone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Hen","incorrectAnswers":["A Sow","A Nanny","A Lioness"],"question":"What would you call a female bird?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Animal Farm","incorrectAnswers":["A Clockwork Orange","L'Ingénu","Nineteen Eighty-Four"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Mr. Jones, of the Manor Farm, had locked the hen-houses for the night, but was too drunk to remember to shut the pop-holes.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Albania","incorrectAnswers":["Algeria","Cameroon","Belgium"],"question":"Tirana is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cote d'Ivoire","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Sudan","Hungary"],"question":"Yamoussoukro is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Dinar","incorrectAnswers":["Lira","Rabat","Reqla"],"question":"What is the basic unit of currency for Tunisia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the studio album 'Good Girl Gone Bad'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vientiane","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra la Vella","Ankara","Apia"],"question":"What is the capital city of Laos?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pigs in blankets","incorrectAnswers":["Little weiners","Swine rolls","Porkos"],"question":"What is the popular name for little baked sausages wrapped in rashers of streaky bacon?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A Lie","incorrectAnswers":["A Disaster","An Accident","A Mistake"],"question":"What is another word for a prevarication?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pantomime","incorrectAnswers":["Colosseum","Theatrical","Cabaret"],"question":"Which word comes from a Greek word meaning 'imitator of all'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Red Devils","incorrectAnswers":["The Canaries","The Blues","The Hoops"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Manchester United?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chaos","incorrectAnswers":["Pandemonium","Bedlam","Anarchy"],"question":"What word, from the Greek mythology, refers to the void from which Nyx and Erebus emerged and is used in English to describe a disordered mess?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1999","incorrectAnswers":["1996","2002","2005"],"question":"The Sixth Sense was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cleopatra","incorrectAnswers":["Imhotep","Tutankhamen","Ramesses"],"question":"At the time of Julius Caesar, who was the ruler of Egypt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Friendly","incorrectAnswers":["Derby","Washer","Double header"],"question":"Which word is used to refer to a soccer match that is not part of an official competition?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A down","incorrectAnswers":["A murder","A cast","A host"],"question":"What is the word for a group of hares?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Napoleon","incorrectAnswers":["Antoinette","Charles de Gaulle","Eclair"],"question":"What is the name of a French pastry known for its flaky layers of puff pastry and pastry cream filling?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Malcolm X","incorrectAnswers":["Martin Luther King","John F Kennedy","Lee Harvey Oswald"],"question":"Who was assassinated on Feb. 21, 1965?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Switzerland ","incorrectAnswers":["The Netherlands","Denmark","France"],"question":"From which country does emmental cheese originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Surrealism","incorrectAnswers":["Abstraction","Poeticism","Pointilism"],"question":"Which art movement explored the unconscious, often using images from dreams?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Meryl Streep","incorrectAnswers":["Glenn Close","Viola Davis","Rooney Mara"],"question":"Who won the 2011 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Margaret Thatcher in The Iron Lady?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Winston Churchill","incorrectAnswers":["Abraham Lincoln","George Washington","Margaret Thatcher"],"question":"Which historic figure's statue, signaling 'V for victory!', stands outside the British embassy in Washington, D.C.?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Anthony Mackie","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Ruffalo","Benedict Cumberbatch","Michael Douglas"],"question":"The role of Falcon in the Marvel Cinematic Universe is played by which actor?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Alanis Morissette","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, dancer and actress released the song 'Hold It Against Me'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tokyo","incorrectAnswers":["Osaka","Okinawa","Shanghai"],"question":"What is the capital city of Japan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Voltaire","incorrectAnswers":["Stendhal","Paulo Coelho","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Encyclopédie'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rear Window","incorrectAnswers":["Fight Club","All About Eve","The Dark Knight"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A wheelchair-bound photographer spies on his neighbors from his apartment.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Advocaat","incorrectAnswers":["Grappa","Brandy","Grand Marnier"],"question":"What liqueur goes into making a 'snowball' cocktail?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"P. Diddy","incorrectAnswers":["Kanye West","Snoop Dogg","Jay Z"],"question":"Which rapper launched their \"Sean John\" fashion line in 1998?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Erik the Red","incorrectAnswers":["Leif Eriksson","King Cnut","Ragnar Lothbrok"],"question":"Who was the father of Leif Eriksson?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Honey, I'm home","incorrectAnswers":["He conquers who endures","So it begins","Every beginning is difficult"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Latin phrase 'Melita, domi adsum!'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Queensboro Bridge ","incorrectAnswers":["Manhattan Bridge","Hudson Bridge","Brooklyn Bridge"],"question":"Which Bridge Features On The Poster To The Woody Allen Film Manhattan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Doors","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Light My Fire'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nevada","incorrectAnswers":["Texas","Oregon","New Mexico"],"question":"Which US state is sandwiched between California and Utah?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Thornton Wilder","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur Miller","Raymond Chandler","Dean Henderson"],"question":"\"Our Town\" is a play by whom?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Zoe Saldana","incorrectAnswers":["Brie Larson","Zendaya","Angelina Jolie"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Gamora in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Through the Looking-Glass","incorrectAnswers":["Mio, My Son","Jonathan Strange & Mr Norrell","The Stand"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'One thing was certain, that the white kitten had had nothing to do with it: — it was the black kitten’s fault entirely.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"United States ","incorrectAnswers":["China","Thailand","Brazil"],"question":"In Which Country Were Fortune Cookies Invented? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Joseph Conrad","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Dickens","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Heart of Darkness'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Central America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","South Africa","Southeast Asia"],"question":"Where was the Aztec Empire located?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"East 17","incorrectAnswers":["Take That","New Kids on the Block","Boyz II Men"],"question":"Which Boyband Released An Album Entitled “Walthamstow” In 1992?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"F. Scott Fitzgerald","incorrectAnswers":["Robert A. Heinlein","James Fenimore Cooper","Donna Leon"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Great Gatsby'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Comet","incorrectAnswers":["Meteor","Moon","Satellite"],"question":"A heavenly body moving under the attraction of the Sun and consisting of a nucleus and a tail is a(n) _______.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"FTP","incorrectAnswers":["SSH","HTTP","SMTP"],"question":"Which networking protocol is used to transfer files between two computers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Secretariat","incorrectAnswers":["Seabiscuit","Man o' War","Affirmed"],"question":"According to his 1989 obituary, which racing legend was survived by more than 600 sons and daughters?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"United most of Western Europe to form the Carolingian Empire.","incorrectAnswers":["King of Macedonia and military leader.","Italian explorer who landed in America.","Social philosopher and pioneer of classical economics."],"question":"Which of the following describes Charlemagne?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"St. Patrick","incorrectAnswers":["St. Peter","St. Paul","St. Augustine"],"question":"Which Roman missionary is credited with bringing Christianity to Ireland in the 5th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","Africa","North America"],"question":"Which is the Earth's largest continent?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Lotus","incorrectAnswers":["Rose","Jasmine","Marigold"],"question":"Which is the national flower of India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Depeche Mode","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Dead or Alive","Radiohead"],"question":"Which English band released the album 'Sounds of the Universe'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Benin","incorrectAnswers":["Malta","Finland","Maldives"],"question":"Porto-Novo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jonathan Swift","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","George Orwell","Samuel Johnson"],"question":"Which satirist wrote 'Gulliver's Travels'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Alcohol By Volume ","incorrectAnswers":["Alcohol Bucahol Variance","Alcoholic Barrier Vitality","Alcoholic Barometric Vice"],"question":"What does the abbreviation A.B.V. Stand for in alcoholic drinks?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gákti","incorrectAnswers":["Kilt","Lederhosen","Bunad"],"question":"Which of these is a piece of traditional clothing worn by the Sami people of Northern Europe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"California ","incorrectAnswers":["Florida","Texas","Kansas"],"question":"Which US state exports the most wine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Flugelhorn","incorrectAnswers":["Cymbal","Cello","Sitar"],"question":"Which of these is a brass instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ride A White Swan","incorrectAnswers":["Children of the Revolution","Cosmic Dancer","Get It On"],"question":"Which T-Rex hit contains the line 'Take a black cat and sit it on your shoulder'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"You’re going to go through life thinking that girls don’t like you because you’re a nerd. And I want you to know, from the bottom of my heart, that won’t be true. It’ll be because you’re an a**hole.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Who's on first.\"","\"Striker: Surely you can't be serious.\"","\"We rob banks.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Social Network'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Karl May","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Ende","Friedrich Engels","Erich Maria Remarque"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Im Schatten des Grossherrn'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chevrolet","incorrectAnswers":["Ford","BMW","Aston Martin"],"question":"The Corvette is a model of car made by which manufacturer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Table tennis","Gymnastics","Motor Racing"],"question":"With which sport is Martina Navratilova associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Julius Caesar","incorrectAnswers":["Augustus Caesar","Marc Anthony","Marcus Licinius Crassus"],"question":"Who said \"Veni, vidi, vici\" (\"I came, I saw, I conquered\")?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Giovanni Boccaccio","incorrectAnswers":["Dante Alighieri","Agatha Christie","Stephenie Meyer"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Dekameron'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Costa Rica","Mongolia","Pakistan"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'White with a large red disk in the center.'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Fleur Delacour' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Mormon Tabernacle","incorrectAnswers":["The Amish Colonade","The Witness Hall","The Jesuit Amphitheatre"],"question":"Which of these is an iconic Salt Lake City building?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Brooklyn Bridge","incorrectAnswers":["The Golden Gate Bridge","Tower Bridge","George Washington Bridge"],"question":"What is the name of the bridge that spans the East River in New York and was the first to use steel for cable wire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Harold Macmillan","incorrectAnswers":["Margaret Thatcher","Winston Churchill","Clement Attlee"],"question":"Who succeeded Anthony Eden as the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom in 1957?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A ballpoint pen","incorrectAnswers":["A typewriter","A book","A lamp"],"question":"In British English, what does a 'Biro' refer to?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ludwig Wittgenstein","incorrectAnswers":["Socrates","Bertrand Russell","Epicurus"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Philosophy is a battle against the bewitchment of our intelligence by means of language'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Frontal Lobe","incorrectAnswers":["Cortex","The Hypothalamus","The Parietal Lobe"],"question":"What Part Of The Brain Is Affected In A Lobotomy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Urge Overkill","Tori Amos","The Zutons"],"question":"The song 'With a Little Help From My Friends' had a well-known cover by Joe Cocker, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Who Wants To Be A Millionaire?","incorrectAnswers":["Jeopardy!","Wheel of Fortune","The Price Is Right"],"question":"What TV game show had a 'Phone-a-Friend' lifeline?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bigfoot","incorrectAnswers":["Loch Ness Monster","Yeti","Chupacabra"],"question":"Which legendary creature is thought to inhabit the forests of North America, standing up to 10 feet tall and weighing about 500 pounds?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Achilles","incorrectAnswers":["Hercules","Perseus","Odysseus"],"question":"Which Ancient Greek hero was invulnerable in all of his body except for one heel?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, actress and record producer released the song 'Video Phone'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Silmarillion","incorrectAnswers":["The Decameron","Dead Souls","Welcome to the N.H.K."],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'There was Eru, the One, who in Arda is called Ilúvatar; and he made first the Ainur, the Holy Ones, that were the offspring of his thought, and they were with him before aught else was made.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Premier12","incorrectAnswers":["The US PGA","The Daytona 500","The ICC World Cup"],"question":"Which of these is a competition in Baseball?","difficulty":"medium"},